### David Lewis, CISA, CISSP

Email: Lewisfmly@gmail.com Tel: 905-763-8941 (Canada)

### **Objective**

Experienced International Security Management Consultant looking to join a Consulting organization's Senior Team as a lead for Security Program Services. Working with this senior team to train and grow professionals to perform these services.

## **Experience and Qualifications**

With over 13 years experience in Information Security, Risk Management and Controls, I have helped international organizations reduce risk by determining their needs and creating solutions to mitigate them.

- > Taken organizations with limited security program to self sustaining in less than nine months.
- > Performed end-to-end opportunity engagement, from sales, Executive presentations, to costing, budget and project management.
- > Lead the Application Security Offering development in IBM Canada this service became an international IBM offering.
- > Managed a Roles Based Access control project to drive Return on Investment (ROI) around application user access management.
- ➤ Supporting the Caribbean Security Sales teams in the Caribbean market.
- > Analyzing, recommending, designing and implementing security, governance, controls programs and solutions for organizations.

## **Lecturing and Conferences**

- > Presented to customers of the Bahamian Chamber of Commerce on "Identity Theft in the world today" in late 2005.
- > Presented to Organizations Executives, clients of the Curacao and Aruba National Bank's on Security program in February 2006.
- ➤ Chosen as one out of 1700 presenters to present at the IBM Technical Leaders Exchange in the US in March 2006.
- > Presented at WebSec 2006 in Mexico on Application Security Controls.
- Developed and presented summer course at Queens University.

## **Membership and Certification**

- ➤ Certified as a Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP) from International Information Systems Security Certification Consortium (ISC²).
- > Certified as a Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA) from Information Systems Audit and Control Association (ISACA).
- ➤ Co-Chairman of IBM's Security Interest Group in 2005/2006.
- > Past Toronto Chapter Lead for The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) in 2005.

### **Employment**

### IBM, Canada: January 2000 to Present

**Managing Consultant:** IBM certified Consultant and senior security team member, Caribbean Security Sales Lead. *Experience:* 

- Acting Chief Security Officer for one of the largest banks in Bahamas.
- > Developed and created marketing and costing for Application Security Offering for Canada became a global offering.
- > Security Program Establishment for financial & Government Agency and Hospital using ISO 17799 as the international standard.
- ➤ Provided security risk, governance services (SOX, Bill 198), organization development and security awareness, program development and implementation.
- > Project managed most of the security projects I have been involved in over the past 13 years.
- ➤ Managed and participated on a project to determine the weaknesses at a retail organization's 450 stores located across Canada and developed a security program that was focused on store environment and risk.
- Managed two world wide vulnerability projects to reduce the risk of 1000's of vulnerabilities for one of the largest banks in Canada.

### David Lewis, CISA, CISSP

Email: Lewisfmly@gmail.com Tel: 905-763-8941 (Canada)

## PWC/Coopers and Lybrand (C&L) Canada: November 1994 – January 2000

Manager: Senior member of the PWC/C&L Security Practice and certified as a contingency planner.

#### Experience:

- ➤ Performed Health Checks, penetration testing, 5900 audits (SAS 70's) for third party service organizations to identify & reduce risk.
- > Evaluated logical and physical security controls based on industry standards, meeting with all levels of the organizations to gather information.
- > Developed business continuity plans using all phases of the development process to provide international and North American companies with contingency strategies to meet their business objectives and risk.
- ➤ Developed the IT Y2K business application and technology plans for PWC Canada. This was rolled out to all offices internationally as a template.
- > Developed the Y2K plans for PWC's IT recovery. These plans were well accepted by the international committee and the template used across the world for all PWC locations.
- ➤ Performed ethical Hacking, war dialing and infrastructure reviews.
- > Designed a security organization for one of the largest banks in Canada which included three companies and teams of security related services spread across the companies. This was to centralize a security team under one umbrella organization with roles defined for each.

## **Wooltru Group South Africa: November 1990 – April 1994**

**Systems Administrator:** Network and system administrator and instrumental in moving the network from Novell to Banyan Vines. *Experience:* 

- > Developed a tool for physical cable testing.
- ➤ Provided Wooltru with their first Internet mail gateway for transmitting internet mail in and out of the Wooltru network using a local Internet Service Provider.
- ➤ Performed security administration on 8 UNIX servers and databases.
- > Assisted in the recovery planning process.
- > Planned and implemented a conversion of PC's from Novell Network Operating System to Banyan Vines.
- ➤ Helped plan and perform a move from Arc net to Ethernet twisted pair for over 400 LAN nodes.
- ➤ Network administrator for the companies 400+ users.
- Supported the LAN equipment, cabling and hubs which included WAN connectivity.

# Coopers and Lybrand (C&L) South Africa: July 1989 - October 1990

**Analyst Developer:** Analyzed customer requirements, developed software, created documentation and provided problem management.

#### Experience:

- ➤ David setup C&L's first network and administered this network, access, groups and rights.
- ➤ Application development, maintenance and expansion/changes for customer applications.
- ➤ Installed and supervised client's Novell networks and security.
- > Provided training for clients software packages.

### South African Defense Force: November 1987 – June 1989

**Lance Corporal:** Compulsory Defense Force served in the personnel unit in computers.

#### Experience:

- Automated the guard duty roster to simplify the entering and scheduling process.
- ➤ Provided training material and trained permanent force staff on how to use computers.
- > Validated changes to recruits personal and medical information and entering this information into the computer.

## Mega Data Solutions South Africa: January 1986 – October 1986

**Programmer:** Analyzed customer requirements and developed applications using the Pick Basic and developed user manuals and documentation.

# **Qualifications**

- ➤ Cape Technikon: 1984 1986 full time Diploma in Computer Data processing
- ➤ Cape Technikon: 1987 1989 part time Higher Diploma in Computer Systems